Finding aid to the Special Events and People collection CA.MS.01002
Smith College Archives
Special Events and People collection
1879-1999
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.01002
17.917 linear feet (43 containers)
The collection contains materials relating to special events and people hosted by Smith College, including files on disasters, anniversaries, lectures and symposiums, and War Service in World War II.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation. Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains materials relating to special events and people hosted by Smith College. Files on Anniversaries include material on college anniversaries in l900, l925, 1950, and 1975. Files on Disasters include news clippings on fires, thefts, murders, disappearances, suicides. Files on Lectures include photographs, press releases, and news clippings on guest lecturers. Files on Prizes include correspondence and news clippings. Symposiums files include correspondence, photographs, programs, news clippings, publications. Files on War Service includes photographs, organization records, news clippings, publications, personal papers of participants, campus and local activities, War Service Board records.
Smith College.
- Anniversaries - 1900 (Box 45)
- Anniversaries - 1925 (Alumnae Association Notices - Invitations) (Box 46)
- Anniversaries - 1925 (News Clippings - Tickets) (Box 47)
- Anniversaries - alumnae pins, 1879-1924 (Box 47a)
- Anniversaries - 1950 Alumnae Fund (Alumnae Clubs - Audit) (Box 48)
- Anniversaries - 1950 Alumnae Fund (Benefits Projects - Commodities) (Box 49)
- Anniversaries - 1950 Alumnae Fund (Community Committee - Districts) (Box 50)
- Anniversaries - 1950 Alumnae Fund (Donors - Individuals) (Box 51)
- Anniversaries - 1950 Alumnae Fund (J.P. Jones Corp. - Northampton Office) (Box 52)
- Anniversaries - 1950 Alumnae Fund (Organization - Workshop Conference) (Box 53)
- Anniversaries - 1950 (Art Museum - Conference) (Box 54)
- Anniversaries - 1950 (Convocation - Exhibits) (Box 55)
- Anniversaries - 1950 (Facts About Smith College - Nicolson) (Box 56)
- Anniversaries - 1950 (Observance Committee - Working Tea) (Box 57)
- Anniversaries - 1950 (Scrapbooks) (Box 58)
- Anniversary - scrapbooks, 1950 (Box 58.1)
- Anniversaries - 1975 (General) (Box 59)
- Anniversaries - 1975 (Postcards and Scrapbooks) (Box 60)
- Anniversaries - Sophia Smith Bicentennial, 1996 (Box 67.24)
- Anniversaries - 1999 (125th) (Box 67.25)
- Disasters - Fires, Murders, Suicides, Thefts (Box 69)
- Disasters - Research Files on Frances St. John Smith Disappearance case, John N. Inglis and Ambrose Smith (Box 69.1)
- Fellowships, Films (Box 78)
- Landscape Architecture Symposium - Material re: alumnae exhibit, 1991-92 (Box 99)
- Lectures, Lecturers - General, Unknown, A-SR (Box 100)
- Lectures, Lecturers - Si-Z (Box 101)
- Lectures - card file (Box 101.1)
- Prizes (Box 102)
- Prizes - Edwin C. Land prize essays (Box 102.1)
- Sophia Smith Award Medal (Box 122)
- Symposiums - book - "Symposium on Art and Morals - Smith College" (Box 127)
- Symposiums - A-R (Box 128)
- Symposiums - S-Z (Box 128.1)
- Symposiums - Land Called Crete (Box 129)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945 - A-B (Box 171)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945 - C-D (Box 172)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945 - E-F (Box 173)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945 - Gift to London - Tea Cars (Mobile Canteens) - London Smith Club (Box 174)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945 - R-Vi (Box 175)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945 - S.S. Smith Victory (ship) - scrapbook (Box 176)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945 - Vo-Z (Box 177)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945 - War Service Board (A-Z), French Relief (Box 178)
- War Service Collection, World War 1939-1945, War Service Board (A-Z), Greek Relief (Box 179)